Finding Aid for James Oliver Curwood papers, 1897-1927
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Paper Originals
  - Movie scenarios
    - The Man of Vengeance (Box 5)
    - A Matter of Ancestry or The Governor's Wife, 2 drafts (Box 5)
    - Nomads of the North, 1919
      - Memo from Curwood to Messrs. Carver, Hartford, Shipman, and Gardner October 8, 1919 (Box 5)
      - Working synopsis written by Curwood (Box 5)
      - Animal action (Box 5)
    - The River's End, 1919 (Box 5)
    - The Unforgettable Crime (Box 5)
    - The Yellow-Back
      - Curwood's notes to accompany scenario (Box 5)
      - Scenario (Box 5)
      - Synopsis (Box 5)
      - Story (Box 5)
      - Copy of synopsis for David Hartford (Box 5)
  - Stenographer's notes
    - 1925-1927, 10 pads (Box 6)
  - Photographs
    - Portraits (Box 6)
    - Ethel Curwood (Box 6)
    - Cabins, exteriors and interiors (Box 6)
    - Camps (Box 6)
    - Canoes and boats (Box 6)
    - Catholic churches in Arctic, bishop on dogsled (Box 6)
    - Farming and ranching (Box 6)
    - Fishing (Box 6)
    - Hunting and trapping (Box 6)
    - Hunting trophies (Box 6)
    - Indians (Box 6)
    - Lumbering (Box 6)
    - Mountains (Box 6)
    - Movie stills (Box 6)
    - Pack horses (Box 6)
    - Saginaw River pollution (Box 6)
    - Transportation, miscellaneous, including railroads and dogsleds (Box 6)
    - Trip to Teddy Brown's (Box 6)
    - Wildlife (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 6)
  - Film
    - God's Country and the Law (Box 6)
      (excerpts) [nitrate original discarded in 1987. VHS and U-Matic videotape copies available].
  - Miscellaneous printed items
    - Cutter, John C. Intermediate Anatomy, Physiology and Hygiene. Philadelphia: J.B. Lippincott Co., 1887 (Box 6)
    - Harper's Fifth Reader: American Authors. New York: Harper & Brothers, 1889 (Box 6)
    - Willson, Marcius. Outlines of History. New York: Ivison & Phinney, 1854 (Box 6)
  - Printed Works
    - The Alaskan. New York: Cosmopolitan, 1923. (Box 7)
    - The Ancient Highway. New York: Cosmopolitan, 1925. (Box 7)
    - Back to God's Country. New York: Grosset & Dunlap, 1920. (Box 7)
    - Baree, Son of Kazan. Garden City: Doubleday, Page, 1917. (Box 7)
    - The Black Hunter. New York: Cosmopolitan, 1926. (Box 7)
    - The Country Beyond. New York: Cosmopolitan, 1922. (Box 7)
    - The Courage of Captain Plum. New York: Grosset & Dunlap, 1912. (Box 7)
    - The Courage of Marge O'Doone. New York: Grosset & Dunlap, 1918. (Box 7)
    - The Crippled Lady of Peribonka. Garden City: Doubleday, Doran, 1929. (Box 7)
    - The Danger Trail. New York: Grosset & Dunlap, 1910. (Box 7)
    - Falkner of the Inland Seas. New York: Books, Inc., 1944. (Box 7)
    - The Flaming Forest. New York: Cosmopolitan, 1921. (Box 7)
    - Flower of the North. New York: Harper & Brothers, 1912. (Box 7)
    - A Gentleman of Courage. New York: Cosmopolitan, 1924. (Box 7)
    - [The Glory of Living. New York: Aeonian Press, 1983. (Box 7)
      Catalogued in DB2 C982 A13 (Reprint of edition of Curwood's autobiography, which may have been published before his death; book from which Son of the Forests, the American version, was derived.)].
    - God's Country - and the Woman. Garden City: Doubleday, Page, 1915. (Box 7)
    - God's Country. New York: Cosmopolitan, 1921. (Box 7)
    - The Gold Hunters. Indianapolis: Bobbs-Merrill, 1909. (Box 7)
    - The Golden Snare. New York: Grosset & Dunlap, 1921. (Box 7)
    - [The Great Lakes. New York: Putnam's, 1909. (Box 7)
      Catalogued in EA 80 C982 G786]
    - Green Timber. New York: Grosset & Dunlap, 1930. (Box 7)
    - The Grizzly King. Garden City: Doubleday, Page, 1923. (Box 7)
    - The Honor of the Big Snows. New York: Triangle Books, 1911. (Box 7)
    - The Hunted Woman. Garden City: Doubleday, Page, 1916. (Box 8)
    - Isobel. New York: Harper & Brothers, 1913. (Box 8)
    - Kazan. New York: Grosset & Dunlap, 1914. (Box 8)
    - Kazan excerpt in My Story That I Like Best, Edna Ferber et. al. New York: International Magazine Co., 1925. (Box 8)
    - Nomads of the North. Garden City: Doubleday, Page, 1919. (Box 8)
    - Philip Steele of the Royal Mounted Police. Indianapolis: Bobbs-Merrill, 1911. (Box 8)
    - The Plains of Abraham. Garden City: Doubleday, Doran, 1928. (Box 8)
    - The River's End. New York: Grosset & Dunlap, 1919. (Box 8)
    - [Son of the Forests. Garden City: Doubleday, Doran, 1930. Catalogued in DB2 C982 A12 (Box 8)
      (Derived, for publication in the United States, from The Glory of Living, which had only been published in England)].
    - Swift Lightning. New York: Grosset & Dunlap, 1926. Two copies. (Box 8)
    - The Valley of Silent Men. New York: Cosmopolitan, 1920. (Box 8)
    - The Wolf Hunters. Indianapolis: Bobbs-Merrill, 1908. (Box 8)
  - Foreign Language Editions
    - Grizli, 1964 (Box 8)
    - Hrabar Dzentlmen, 1964 (Box 8)
    - Kapetan Plum 1964. (Box 8)
    - Kazan, volcji pes, 1962 (Box 8)
    - Kocovnici Severu 1962 (Box 8)
    - Kral sedych medvedu 1967 (Box 8)
    - Lutalice Sa Severa 1965 (Box 8)
    - Medvjedic Niva 1967 (Box 8)
    - Na Kraju Sveta 1964 (Box 8)
    - Nomades du Nord, Un Gentleman Courageux, La Piste du Bonheur, 1968 (Box 8)
  - Ivan Conger Accession, 1994
    - Volume I 1/1/1901-12/1/1920, 3 folders (Box 9)
    - Volume II 12/1/1920-12/31/1921, 3 folders (Box 9)
    - Volume III 1/1/1922-12/31/1923, 3 folders (Box 9)
    - Volume IV 1/1/1921-12/31/1924, 3 folders (Box 9)
    - Volume V 1920s (Box 9)
Partial Index to Correspondents
Babbitt, Rube S.
July 7, 1922; December 21, 1926; January 8, January 20, March 19, 1927.
Baird, John, 1860-
December 8, 1920; January 5, April 4, November 25, December 20, December 24, 1921; June 13, 1922; January 11, January 16, January 18, 1926.
Brown, Curtis
February 9, March 5, April 14, May 19, June 2, July 1, 1914; February 2, February 16, March 9, March 22, 1915
March 2, June 28, 1921.
Dilg, Will H.
September 16, September 26, September 30, October 3, October 28, December 15, December 20, December 23, December 27, December 30, 1922; January 2, January 6, January 25, February 13, April 9, October 24, 1923
February 26, April 5, 1924; June 19, June 29, July 10, July 17, August 30, September 7, November 20, 1926.
Doubleday, Russell, 1872-1949
January 5, January 12, February 16, August 2, August 30, December 17, 1918.
Essanay Film Manufacturing Co.
September 16, October 7, August 1, September 18, 1912
February 18, April 4, May 2, October 24, November 6, 1913
October 23, October 29, 1920.
Fletcher, Richard H.
September 1, September 5, September 6, September 7, September 8, September 9, September 20, October 4, 1922.
Glaspie, Andrew Bird, 1876-
January 3, 1922; March 14, 1923; December 14, December 18, December 26, 1926.
Green, Fred Warren, 1872-1936
April 15, April 25, April 26, 1922; September 20, September 25, September 29, November 13, December 21, December 31, 1926; January 4, January 22, January 25, January 27, February 23, March 2, March 18, June 30, 1927.
Hartford, David M.
November 1919-August 1921, throughout; October 4, October 10, December 22, 1921.
Hubbs, Carl Leavitt, 1894-
December 12, December 23, 1921.
Kinsey, Harold C.
January 1919-October 1921, throughout.
Long, Ray, 1878-1935
January 1919-May 1921, throughout; July 15, July 22, September 8, September 15, October 7, 1921.
Lovejoy, Parish Storrs
December 14, December 15, 1921; January 28, February 4, March 20, August 22, September 23, September 30, October 24, October 30, November 13, 1922; December 23, 1926.
Marston, Thomas Frank, 1869-
July 15, July 18, 1921.
Mayer, Louis Burt, 1885-1957
January 15, 1920.
Michigan State Park Commission
May 19, 1920; September 23, 1921.
Montrose, Joseph
May 1920-July 1921, throughout.
Mott, Charles Stewart, 1875-1973
December 14, December 27, 1922; January 26, February 19, February 23, 1923.
Pinchot, Gifford, 1865-1946.
February 2, 1923.
Roth, Filibert, 1858-1925
October 1, October 3, December 8, December 13, December 14, December 27, December 29, December 31, 1921
January 2, November 1, 1922; February 14, 1923.
Stoll, Albert, 1884-
September 12, September 15, September 25, September 27, December 1, 1921; Undated, February 16, February 25, April 10, April 20, 1922; January 10, April 10, April 14, April 16, July 18, 1923.
Titus, Harold, 1888-1967
January 25, January 27, June 6, June 30, July 14, July 19, 1927.
Vandenberg, Arthur Hendrick, 1884-1951
December 22, December 23, 1921; January 26, 1922.
Voght, Edward C.
March 16, May 8, May 10, July 7, July 10, July 26, September 13, October 4, December 23, December 27, 1922.
Wallace, Henry Cantwell. 1866-1924
February 13, February 26, March 7, March 31, April 28, May 2, May 4, 1923.
Watson, Russell
January 3, November 7, November 10, December 10, December 14, 1922; January 1, February 12, February 14, 1923.
Young, Leigh Jarvis, 1883-1960
Undated, February 21, March 19, May 17, May 21, May 25, June 3, July 8, July 15, August 9, 1927.
Zeigen, Frederic H., 1874-
November 18, 1918; April 5, 1920.
Partial Index Correspondence by Subjects
Deer Herd Management
November 27, December 14, 1921; June-July 1927, throughout.
Forest Fire Protection
July 18, October 14, November 1, December 14, 1921; February 2, February 3, February 4, 1922; February 1, 1927.
Sport Fishing Issues
January 9, November 6, 1922; January 25, 1923; Undated, January 18, January 21, June 24, June 25, June 27, June 30, July 2, July 7, July 16, July 18, August 6, 1927.
Water Pollution
August 9, 1918; December 8, 1920; February 11, April 18, December 3, December 12, December 23, 1921; February 10, July 3, July 18, August 6, October 18, November 9, 1923.